





# mrhowel@g.clemson.edu (864)-508-0676 howell-info.us Easley, SC

# MATTHEW HOWELL

### **SUMMARY**

Technology has been a passion for me most of my life and I love both sharing it with others and using my experience to help everyone reap the maximum benefits from technology. I have three years of experience in IT support roles and hands on experience with many technologies through experimentation in my home lab environment.

#### **EDUCATION**

May 2018 Computer Science, BS

Clemson University, 3.36 GPA

# **PROJECTS**

Present – 2017

Personal Website (howell-info.us) - Webmaster

Personal website to display other projects. Previously hosted on

AWS EC2 but now hosted using Azure Web App.

May 2018 – Feb 2018 Resident Assistant Tiger Talk Tracker – Front-End & API Created a web application for Resident Assistants to submit

their Tiger Talk reports as well as review and gather statistics

about the reports.

Dec 2017 – Jan 2017 **VR Animation Program – Locomotion & Controls** 

VR Program developed using C# in Unity for the Oculus Rift headset. Users can import custom models and use them to create and save stop-motion animations. Program includes a 3D environment for users to explore and animate in.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Current – Dec 2018 Alorica, SmartThings Support Specialist

- Provide phone/email support for Samsung SmartThings products
- Document customer interactions
- Troubleshoot device and connectivity issues

May 2018 – Aug 2015 Clemson University, IT Support Assistant

- Provided on-site, telephone, and remote assistance to university faculty, staff and graduate students
- Provided purchase recommendations for desktop peripherals
- Assisted with maintenance of AD
- Assisted users with Exchange accounts across MacOS, Windows, Android, and iOS
- Provided training for new student workers
- Managed Tickets using BMC Footprints

Feb 2015 – Aug 2014 Wal-Mart Inc., Electronics Sales Associate

- Determined customer needs and assisted with hardware purchase recommendations
- Maintained organization of department

# Information Technology Full Stack Development

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

Docker AWS S3 Ansible AWS EC2

Git Azure Web Apps

Qemu/KVM Bootstrap LVM Redis MDADM Proxmox

TCP/IP

# **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

Windows iOS
MacOS Android
Linux

#### LANGUAGES

HTML PHP CSS Javascript

C++ C#

### Related Skills & Hobbies

Home Lab Environment

Freelance IT Consulting & Support

A+ Certified (Expired 5/12/2017)